Help on function fit in module statsmodels.tsa.statespace.dynamic_factor_mq:

fit(
    self,
    start_params=None,
    transformed=True,
    includes_fixed=False,
    cov_type='none',
    cov_kwds=None,
    method='em',
    maxiter=500,
    tolerance=1e-06,
    em_initialization=True,
    mstep_method=None,
    full_output=1,
    disp=False,
    callback=None,
    return_params=False,
    optim_score=None,
    optim_complex_step=None,
    optim_hessian=None,
    flags=None,
    low_memory=False,
    llf_decrease_action='revert',
    llf_decrease_tolerance=0.0001,
    **kwargs
)
    Fits the model by maximum likelihood via Kalman filter.

    Parameters
    ----------
    start_params : array_like, optional
        Initial guess of the solution for the loglikelihood maximization.
        If None, the default is given by Model.start_params.
    transformed : bool, optional
        Whether or not `start_params` is already transformed. Default is
        True.
    includes_fixed : bool, optional
        If parameters were previously fixed with the `fix_params` method,
        this argument describes whether or not `start_params` also includes
        the fixed parameters, in addition to the free parameters. Default
        is False.
    cov_type : str, optional
        The `cov_type` keyword governs the method for calculating the
        covariance matrix of parameter estimates. Can be one of:

        - 'opg' for the outer product of gradient estimator
        - 'oim' for the observed information matrix estimator, calculated
          using the method of Harvey (1989)
        - 'approx' for the observed information matrix estimator,
          calculated using a numerical approximation of the Hessian matrix.
        - 'robust' for an approximate (quasi-maximum likelihood) covariance
          matrix that may be valid even in the presence of some
          misspecifications. Intermediate calculations use the 'oim'
          method.
        - 'robust_approx' is the same as 'robust' except that the
          intermediate calculations use the 'approx' method.
        - 'none' for no covariance matrix calculation.

        Default is 'none', since computing this matrix can be very slow
        when there are a large number of parameters.
    cov_kwds : dict or None, optional
        A dictionary of arguments affecting covariance matrix computation.

        **opg, oim, approx, robust, robust_approx**

        - 'approx_complex_step' : bool, optional - If True, numerical
          approximations are computed using complex-step methods. If False,
          numerical approximations are computed using finite difference
          methods. Default is True.
        - 'approx_centered' : bool, optional - If True, numerical
          approximations computed using finite difference methods use a
          centered approximation. Default is False.
    method : str, optional
        The `method` determines which solver from `scipy.optimize`
        is used, and it can be chosen from among the following strings:

        - 'em' for the EM algorithm
        - 'newton' for Newton-Raphson
        - 'nm' for Nelder-Mead
        - 'bfgs' for Broyden-Fletcher-Goldfarb-Shanno (BFGS)
        - 'lbfgs' for limited-memory BFGS with optional box constraints
        - 'powell' for modified Powell's method
        - 'cg' for conjugate gradient
        - 'ncg' for Newton-conjugate gradient
        - 'basinhopping' for global basin-hopping solver

        The explicit arguments in `fit` are passed to the solver,
        with the exception of the basin-hopping solver. Each
        solver has several optional arguments that are not the same across
        solvers. See the notes section below (or scipy.optimize) for the
        available arguments and for the list of explicit arguments that the
        basin-hopping solver supports.
    maxiter : int, optional
        The maximum number of iterations to perform.
    tolerance : float, optional
        Tolerance to use for convergence checking when using the EM
        algorithm. To set the tolerance for other methods, pass
        the optimizer-specific keyword argument(s).
    full_output : bool, optional
        Set to True to have all available output in the Results object's
        mle_retvals attribute. The output is dependent on the solver.
        See LikelihoodModelResults notes section for more information.
    disp : bool, optional
        Set to True to print convergence messages.
    callback : callable callback(xk), optional
        Called after each iteration, as callback(xk), where xk is the
        current parameter vector.
    return_params : bool, optional
        Whether or not to return only the array of maximizing parameters.
        Default is False.
    optim_score : {'harvey', 'approx'} or None, optional
        The method by which the score vector is calculated. 'harvey' uses
        the method from Harvey (1989), 'approx' uses either finite
        difference or complex step differentiation depending upon the
        value of `optim_complex_step`, and None uses the built-in gradient
        approximation of the optimizer. Default is None. This keyword is
        only relevant if the optimization method uses the score.
    optim_complex_step : bool, optional
        Whether or not to use complex step differentiation when
        approximating the score; if False, finite difference approximation
        is used. Default is True. This keyword is only relevant if
        `optim_score` is set to 'harvey' or 'approx'.
    optim_hessian : {'opg','oim','approx'}, optional
        The method by which the Hessian is numerically approximated. 'opg'
        uses outer product of gradients, 'oim' uses the information
        matrix formula from Harvey (1989), and 'approx' uses numerical
        approximation. This keyword is only relevant if the
        optimization method uses the Hessian matrix.
    low_memory : bool, optional
        If set to True, techniques are applied to substantially reduce
        memory usage. If used, some features of the results object will
        not be available (including smoothed results and in-sample
        prediction), although out-of-sample forecasting is possible.
        Note that this option is not available when using the EM algorithm
        (which is the default for this model). Default is False.
    llf_decrease_action : {'ignore', 'warn', 'revert'}, optional
        Action to take if the log-likelihood decreases in an EM iteration.
        'ignore' continues the iterations, 'warn' issues a warning but
        continues the iterations, while 'revert' ends the iterations and
        returns the result from the last good iteration. Default is 'warn'.
    llf_decrease_tolerance : float, optional
        Minimum size of the log-likelihood decrease required to trigger a
        warning or to end the EM iterations. Setting this value slightly
        larger than zero allows small decreases in the log-likelihood that
        may be caused by numerical issues. If set to zero, then any
        decrease will trigger the `llf_decrease_action`. Default is 1e-4.
    **kwargs
        Additional keyword arguments to pass to the optimizer.

    Returns
    -------
    MLEResults

    See Also
    --------
    statsmodels.base.model.LikelihoodModel.fit
    statsmodels.tsa.statespace.mlemodel.MLEResults

