Help on function news in module statsmodels.tsa.statespace.mlemodel:

news(
    self,
    comparison,
    impact_date=None,
    impacted_variable=None,
    start=None,
    end=None,
    periods=None,
    exog=None,
    comparison_type=None,
    revisions_details_start=False,
    state_index=None,
    return_raw=False,
    tolerance=1e-10,
    **kwargs
)
    Compute impacts from updated data (news and revisions)

    Parameters
    ----------
    comparison : array_like or MLEResults
        An updated dataset with updated and/or revised data from which the
        news can be computed, or an updated or previous results object
        to use in computing the news.
    impact_date : int, str, or datetime, optional
        A single specific period of impacts from news and revisions to
        compute. Can also be a date string to parse or a datetime type.
        This argument cannot be used in combination with `start`, `end`, or
        `periods`. Default is the first out-of-sample observation.
    impacted_variable : str, list, array, or slice, optional
        Observation variable label or slice of labels specifying that only
        specific impacted variables should be shown in the News output. The
        impacted variable(s) describe the variables that were *affected* by
        the news. If you do not know the labels for the variables, check
        the `endog_names` attribute of the model instance.
    start : int, str, or datetime, optional
        The first period of impacts from news and revisions to compute.
        Can also be a date string to parse or a datetime type. Default is
        the first out-of-sample observation.
    end : int, str, or datetime, optional
        The last period of impacts from news and revisions to compute.
        Can also be a date string to parse or a datetime type. Default is
        the first out-of-sample observation.
    periods : int, optional
        The number of periods of impacts from news and revisions to
        compute.
    exog : array_like, optional
        Array of exogenous regressors for the out-of-sample period, if
        applicable.
    comparison_type : {None, 'previous', 'updated'}
        This denotes whether the `comparison` argument represents a
        *previous* results object or dataset or an *updated* results object
        or dataset. If not specified, then an attempt is made to determine
        the comparison type.
    revisions_details_start : bool, int, str, or datetime, optional
        The period at which to beging computing the detailed impacts of
        data revisions. Any revisions prior to this period will have their
        impacts grouped together. If a negative integer, interpreted as
        an offset from the end of the dataset. If set to True, detailed
        impacts are computed for all revisions, while if set to False, all
        revisions are grouped together. Default is False. Note that for
        large models, setting this to be near the beginning of the sample
        can cause this function to be slow.
    state_index : array_like, optional
        An optional index specifying a subset of states to use when
        constructing the impacts of revisions and news. For example, if
        `state_index=[0, 1]` is passed, then only the impacts to the
        observed variables arising from the impacts to the first two
        states will be returned. Default is to use all states.
    return_raw : bool, optional
        Whether or not to return only the specific output or a full
        results object. Default is to return a full results object.
    tolerance : float, optional
        The numerical threshold for determining zero impact. Default is
        that any impact less than 1e-10 is assumed to be zero.

    Returns
    -------
    NewsResults
        Impacts of data revisions and news on estimates

    References
    ----------
    .. [1] Ba\u0144bura, Marta, and Michele Modugno.
           "Maximum likelihood estimation of factor models on datasets with
           arbitrary pattern of missing data."
           Journal of Applied Econometrics 29, no. 1 (2014): 133-160.
    .. [2] Ba\u0144bura, Marta, Domenico Giannone, and Lucrezia Reichlin.
           "Nowcasting."
           The Oxford Handbook of Economic Forecasting. July 8, 2011.
    .. [3] Ba\u0144bura, Marta, Domenico Giannone, Michele Modugno, and Lucrezia
           Reichlin.
           "Now-casting and the real-time data flow."
           In Handbook of economic forecasting, vol. 2, pp. 195-237.
           Elsevier, 2013.

